Guide to the Sholom Secunda Papers Ca. 1926-1971 MSS 054
Fales Library and Special Collections
Sholom Secunda Papers
ca. 1926-1971
MSS 054
Fales Library and Special Collections
64.0 linear feet (111 boxes)
Sholom Secunda was a composer, arranger, director and critic who came to New York in 1907, and entered the Institute of Musical Art (later renamed the Juilliard School) where he trained with composer Ernest Bloch. Secunda's first love was classical music, but he first supported himself while a young student working as an extra in the Yiddish theater. In Yiddish theater, he found considerable success as a composer and director until the early 1970's. His compositions have been successful both inside and outside the Yiddish theater with hit songs sung by such artists as: the Andrews Sisters and Joan Baez. The bulk of the Sholom Secunda Collection is comprised of music manuscripts for Yiddish Theatre productions, Cantorial music, Liturgical music, Art Songs, Secular Songs and Folk Songs.
Provenance
The Sholom Secunda Papers were the gift of the Secunda family to the Fales Library. The collection was originally organized before 1993 by a student under the supervision of Maxime LaFantasie. Further processing of the papers was done by Cantor, Doris Cohen, Secunda's associate, and Neil Bindelglass.
Access Restrictions
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival materials.
Historical/Biographical Note:
As a small child in the Ukraine, Secunda was known as a "boy cantor". He came to America in 1907 and immediately began singing in public. In 1914, he entered the Institute of Musical Art (later renamed the Juilliard School) and his extensive classical training included private lessons with composer Ernest Bloch. To support himself while a young student, he worked as an extra in the Yiddish theater.
While Secunda's first love was classical music, his livelihood came from his Yiddish theater compositions. For the 1916-17 season, he was engaged as resident composer and conductor for Brooklyn's Lyric Theater. In 1932, Secunda wrote the music for M'ken Lebn nor m'lazt nit (I would if I could) starring Aaron Lebedev and Lucy Levine. Included in the score was the song "Bei Mir Bist Du Sheyn" which when sung by the Andrew Sisters a few years later became the most popular worldwide hit of 1939.
From 1937 into the early 40's, Secunda was the composer for Maurice Schwartz's Yiddish Art Theater writing music for The Brother's Ashkenazi which toured North America and Europe. In 1940, Secunda composed the score for the popular musical Esterke which included "Dona, Dona, Dona" a song that was to resurface 25 years later as an international hit recorded by Joan Baez and others.
In the 1940s, he began working in radio, and from 1946 he was the music critic of the Jewish Daily Forward. In 1951, he wrote music for the Broadway review, Bagels and Lox. From 1945 to 1973, he was the music director of the Concord Hotel, where stars of the Yiddish theater (and many of the great stars of Broadway, Vaudeville, television, and movies) regularly appeared. At the Concord he also composed large amounts of Jewish liturgical music and regularly conducted performances of classical music with well-known classical musicians and opera singers.
Other Secunda compositions include America (1915); Honor Thy Father, (1923); Dos Yidishe Lid (1923); Faith Alone (1937); Dream of Me (1938); and the music for The Kosher Widow starring Molly Picon. His last musical score was for the 1973 production of Sholom Aleichem's Shver tsu Zayn a Yid. This show, starring Joseph Buloff and Miriam Kressyn is considered the last great production of the Yiddish stage.
His wife Betty Almer, the daughter of a Yiddish actress, was a dancer on the Yiddish stage before her marriage to Secunda in 1927. They met during rehearsals for Secunda's musical Margarita. They had two sons: Eugene and Sheldon.
Written by Ben Torpey, 1998
Scope and Content Note
The Sholom Secunda Papers are a part of the Archive and Manuscript Collection at the Fales Library, New York University. The Fales Library is the primary special collections division of the NYU libraries, housing 200,000 volumes of English and American literature from 1700 to the present. Strengths of the collection include the development of the English and American novel, with an emphasis on the Gothic and the Victorian novel.
The bulk of the Sholom Secunda Collection is comprised of Music Manuscripts. These include manuscripts for Yiddish Theatre productions, Cantorial music, Liturgical music, Art Songs, Secular Songs and Folk Songs. Included with the collection are several sound recordings, in various media. These recordings include 78 RPMs, open reel tape, acetate transcription discs and cassettes. There is an extensive collection of Secunda's personal correspondence included in the collection. Also represented is a collection of published sheet music, written by Secunda as well as other composers. Photographs, a single daguerreotype, a book entitled "Daily Prayers," newspaper clippings and the manuscript of a Sholom Secunda biography round out the collection.
SERIES:
I. Musical Theater: scores and parts for theatrical productions
II. Cantorial: scores and parts for cantorial works
III. Vocal Music in English
IV. Instrumental Music
V. Sacred Music
VI. Secular Music
VII. Art Songs: some on liturgical text, but not liturgical works
VIII. Hebrew Songs
IX. Orchestral Arrangements
X. Arrangements (Folk and Theater)
XI. Goldfadn Arrangements
XII. Published Music (Liturgical and Orchestral)
XIII. Oratorios
XIV. Symphonic Poem
XV. Services
XVI. Miscellaneous (Theater and Film)
XVII. Photographs
XVIII. Secunda's Belongings
XIX. Correspondence
XX. Sound Recordings (Acetates and Commercial). [Research copies may not be available for these materials yet. Check with the Fales archivist.]
XXI. Related Materials (notes for biography, translations, etc.)
Arrangement
Series I: Musical Theater
Series II: Cantorial
Series III: Vocal Music in English
Series IV: Instrumental Music
Series V: Sacred Music
Series VI: Secular
Series VII: Art Songs
Series VIII: Hebrew Songs - Arrangements
Series IX: Orchestral Arrangements
Series X: Arrangements (Folk and Theater)
Series XI: Goldfaden Arrangements
Series XII: Published Music (Liturgical and Orchestral)
Series XIII: Oratorios
Series XIV: Symphonic Poem
Series XV: Services
Series XVI: Miscellaneous
Series XVII: Photographs
Series XVIII: Secunda's Belongings
Series XIX: Correspondence
Series XX: Sound Recordings (Acetates and Commercial)
Series XXI: Related Materials
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject/title heading within each series.
The materials are grouped into 21 series. The collection has been processed to the box level.
The initial processing of the collection was done by song title or piece and a card drawer with handwritten cards allowed access to the archive. Unfortunately, the processing was often inaccurate. Funding was subsequently made available to reprocess the papers, and through a donation by the family, to add Secunda materials to the Fales Library that were on deposit at New York Public Library's, Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, bringing the bulk of the Secunda materials together in one collection.
The re-processing of the papers was done by Cantor, Doris Cohen, Secunda's associate, who thoughtfully and methodically reconstructed shows, identified fragments, and sorted the theatrical, liturgical, and art music into separate categories. Without Ms. Cohen, the collection could not have been made so accessible. Neil Bindelglass, likewise, oversaw the creation of the finding aid and the final processing of the papers. Without his extensive knowledge of Yiddish, of music, and of best archival practice, the collection could not have been completed.
Adler, Celia, 1899-1979; Goldfaden, Abraham, 1840-1908; Jacobs, Jacob; Picon, Molly; Secunda, Sholom, 1894-1974; Audiotapes.; Clippings (information artifacts); Composers, Jewish |z United States.; Correspondence.; Folk songs, Yiddish.; Musical theater |z New York (N.Y.); New York (N.Y.); Performing arts |x Production and direction.; Phonograph records.; Photographs.; Sacred music |x Jewish.; Scores.; Scripts (documents); Sheet music.; Songs, Yiddish.; Theater programs.; Theater |x Production and direction.; Theater, Yiddish |z New York (State) |z New York.; Theatrical companies |z New York (State) |z New York.; Yiddish theater |z United States.
- Series I. Musical Theater
  - Antlofene Manner, undated (Box 1A)
    General note
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061815 2
  - Baker's Sweetheart, undated (Box 1A)
  - Bay Mir Bist Du Sheyn, undated (Box 1A)
  - Berele Tramp, undated (Box 1B)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061816 0
  - BrothersAshkenazi, undated (Box 1B)
  - Be Happy, undated (Box 2)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061817 8
  - Be Happy, undated (Box 3)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061818 6
  - A Cowboy in Israel, undated (Box 4)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061819 4
  - Dem Rebn's Kheyshik, undated (Box 5)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061820 2
  - Der Mentsh Fun Morgen, undated (Box 5)
  - Der T'Hilim Yid, undated (Box 5)
  - Der Yiddisher Zinger, undated (Box 6)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061821 0
  - Di Amerkanen Rebbitzim, undated (Box 6)
  - Di Grin Kale, undated (Box 7)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061822 8
  - DiGassen Zinger, undated (Box 7)
  - Di Kale Hot Farblondzhet, undated (Box 7)
  - DiYiddishe Shikse, undated (Box 8)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061823 6
  - East Side Wedding, undated (Box 8)
  - Farblibn Is der Nign, undated (Box 9)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061824 4
  - Game of Love, undated (Box 9)
  - Gimpl Takes a Wife, undated (Box 9)
  - Happy Family, undated (Box 10)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061825 1
  - Hardto be Honest, undated (Box 10)
  - Hearts for Sale, undated (Box 11)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061826 9
  - Heaven onEarth, undated (Box 11)
  - I Would if I Could, undated (Box 12)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061827 7
  - [Bei Mir Bistu Shein], undated (Box 12)
  - If I were Rothschild, undated (Box 12)
  - In Every Home, undated (Box 13)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061828 5
  - In the Name of G-d, undated (Box 13)
  - It Could Happen to You, undated (Box 13)
  - Jakele Bluffer, undated (Box 14)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061829 3
  - A Jewish Romance, undated (Box 14)
  - Kutaz's Wedding, undated (Box 15)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061830 1
  - Kinder Kumt Aheyn, undated (Box 15)
  - KosherWidow, undated (Box 16)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061831 9
  - Laugh and be Happy, undated (Box 17)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061832 7
  - Lend Me Your Head, undated (Box 17)
  - Love on Credit, undated (Box 18)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061833 5
  - Let's Get Married, undated (Box 18)
  - Lucky Days, undated (Box 19)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061834 3
  - Margarita, undated (Box 20)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061835 0
  - Maske, undated (Box 21)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061836 8
  - Mayn Zun Un Ikh, undated (Box 22)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061837 6
  - Nice People, undated (Box 22)
  - A Night in Budapest, undated (Box 23)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061838 4
  - A Night in Oklahoma, undated (Box 23)
  - Oh Girls, undated (Box 24)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061839 2
  - Oy, Amerike, undated (Box 24)
  - Oy Iz Dos aVelt, undated (Box 25)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061840 0
  - Pinze fun Pinchev, undated (Box 26)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061841 8
  - The Poor Millionaire, undated (Box 27)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061842 6
  - Reyzele Fun Slobodka, undated (Box 27)
  - Rich Uncle, undated (Box 27)
  - Senorita, undated (Box 28)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061843 4
  - Sender Blank, undated (Box 28)
  - Sister Love, undated (Box 28)
  - Shulamita, undated (Box 28)
  - The Shepherd King, undated (Box 29)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061844 2
  - A Sheyner Kholem, undated (Box 29)
  - Shukamis, undated (Box 29)
  - Song ofLove, undated (Box 30)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061845 9
  - Street Singers, undated (Box 30)
  - Zise Moment'm, undated (Box 31)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061846 7
  - Three Cities, undated (Box 32)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061847 5
  - Toyzente Vayber, undated (Box 32)
  - TwoHundred Thousand, undated (Box 32)
  - Uncle Sam in Israel, undated (Box 33)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061848 3
  - Uncle Sam in Israel, undated (Box 34)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061849 1
  - UnzerToyrele, undated (Box 35)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061850 9
  - We Shall Live, undated (Box 35)
  - When Hearts are Young, undated (Box 35)
  - Who's Who, undated (Box 35)
  - When Love Calls, undated (Box 36)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061851 7
  - Yankele Karmantshik, undated (Box 36)
  - Yosele Slovey, undated (Box 36)
  - Yoshe Kalb, undated (Box 36)
  - Wive on Conditions, undated (Box 37)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061852 5
  - ZaynYiddish Meydl, undated (Box 38)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061853 3
  - Zol Zayn Mit Mazl, undated (Box 39)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061854 1
  - Esterke, undated (Box 40)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061855 8
- Series II. Cantorial
  - Ashrey Haish -"Happy is the man [who trusts in you]", undated (Box 41)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061856 6
  - Av HaRakhomim -, undated (Box 41)
  - Avinu Malkeinu Z'khor - "Our Father Our King remembers that we are dust", undated (Box 41)
  - Al Moley Ha Rakhomim - "O merciful G-d full of compassion", undated (Box 41)
  - Eloheinu Velohei Avoseinu - "O G-d and G-d of our ancesors", undated (Box 41)
  - Haish Kiveinu - "Cause us o Lord our G-d", undated (Box 41)
  - Hineni Heoni MiMa'as - "Behold me of little merit, as I stand before you to, undated (Box 41)
  - plead for your people", undated (Box 41)
  - Kidush, undated (Box 41)
  - KidushKineret Sheli, L'Shana HaBa'a, undated (Box 41)
  - Kol K'Shimeyo - "This is your glory.Your fame like your name is hallowed", undated (Box 41)
  - Kol Omar Ad haShem - "Thus said the lord", undated (Box 42)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061857 4
  - L'Al Barukh - "To the blessed G-d", undated (Box 42)
  - Mimkomkho - "Throughout your universe", undated (Box 42)
  - RokhelMevako - "Rachael weeps", undated (Box 42)
  - Rebeinu Shel Olam - "Counting of the omen", undated (Box 42)
  - Shiro Az Yoshir, undated (Box 42)
  - Tikanto Shabos - "Shabbat have you established", undated (Box 42)
  - Tsadik Adonoi - "The Lord is riteous in all His ways,and holy in all His works", undated (Box 42)
  - Va'anachnu Lo Neida - "Uncertain of our ways,we look to You", undated (Box 42)
  - Yehi Ratson - "May it be Your will", undated (Box 42)
  - Yir'u Eineinu - "May our eyes behold", undated (Box 42)
- Series III. Vocal Music in English
  - Declaration for Baritone, undated (Box 43)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061858 2
  - Doina Vocalise, undated (Box 43)
  - Faith Alone, undated (Box 43)
  - The Flower of Beauty, undated (Box 43)
  - The Golden Wedding, undated (Box 43)
  - I'll Gather Stars, undated (Box 43)
  - Love For You I Live, undated (Box 44)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061859 0
  - There's One Lord for All, undated (Box 44)
- Series IV. Instrumental Music
  - American Calling, undated (Box 45)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061860 8
  - Ballet Suite (Sheydin Veys'n Vos), undated (Box 45)
  - Chamber Ensemble with Pianl, undated (Box 45)
  - Chassidic Potpourri (Cello part only), undated (Box 45)
  - Chassidic Suite for Strings, undated (Box 45)
  - Ch'sidic, undated (Box 45)
  - Concert Freylakhs (Hebrew Rhapsody No 2), undated (Box 45)
  - Dance (Violin Solo), undated (Box 45)
  - Droshah, undated (Box 45)
  - Imperssions, undated (Box 45)
  - Jewish Dance, undated (Box 45)
  - Nuskhaot (Concerto of the Cantillations), undated (Box 46)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061861 6
  - Oriental Waltz, undated (Box 46)
  - Palestiner Libe, undated (Box 46)
  - Pessimism and Death, undated (Box 46)
  - Piano Solo(Untitled), undated (Box 46)
  - Poor Gypsy, undated (Box 46)
  - Prelude andFugue, undated (Box 46)
  - Quartet, undated (Box 46)
  - Quartet, undated (Box 46)
  - Quartet in Cminor, undated (Box 46)
  - Romanze in B Minor, undated (Box 46)
  - Scherzo and Rondo, undated (Box 46)
  - Veyn Kalle Veyn - Kalle Bazets'n, undated (Box 46)
  - Violin Solo, undated (Box 46)
  - Yiddish, undated (Box 46)
  - Yiddish Rhapsody, undated (Box 46)
- Series V.Sacred Music
  - Adonoy Roi (23rd Psalm - "The Lord is My Shepherd"), undated (Box 47)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061862 4
  - B'MotsoeiM'nucho, undated (Box 47)
  - Lishmoa al Horino, undated (Box 47)
  - B'ruchim Atem, undated (Box 47)
  - Eilu Dvarim, undated (Box 47)
  - Kabed Es Ovicho, undated (Box 47)
  - Im Eshkocheich, undated (Box 47)
  - Mi Sheoso, undated (Box 47)
  - M'nuchoV"Simcho, undated (Box 47)
  - Omar Adoshem L'Ya"akov, undated (Box 47)
  - KoOmar Adoshem, undated (Box 48)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061863 2
  - R'tzei Asirom, undated (Box 48)
  - Sheyiboneh, undated (Box 48)
  - Beis Hamikdosh, undated (Box 48)
  - Ten to Tame Tyranny, undated (Box 48)
  - Tsadik Adonoy, undated (Box 48)
  - V'Al Y'dei, undated (Box 48)
  - V'hu Rachum, undated (Box 48)
  - Tzedek L'Fonov Y'Holech, undated (Box 48)
- Series VI.Secular:
  - Amcho, undated (Box 49)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061864 0
  - Bar Mitzvah Sone, undated (Box 49)
  - Chassidisher Nigun, undated (Box 49)
  - Der Oybershter In Der Mechuten, undated (Box 49)
  - Der Heymisher Nigun, undated (Box 49)
  - Der Shadkhen, undated (Box 49)
  - Di Heylige Troyke, undated (Box 49)
  - Di Libe, undated (Box 49)
  - Fort Tsu Mayn Tebn, undated (Box 49)
  - Foters, undated (Box 49)
  - Gilo Rino, undated (Box 49)
  - Harts Mayns, undated (Box 49)
  - Hertser Fargesen Nit, undated (Box 49)
  - Hob a Harts, undated (Box 49)
  - Ikh Bin aBoarder Bay Mayn Vayb, undated (Box 49)
  - In a Litvisher Dorf, undated (Box 49)
  - Kosher Tants, undated (Box 49)
  - Libe Vet ifinen a Veg, undated (Box 49)
  - LikhtBentsh'n, undated (Box 49)
  - A Mame Fehlt, undated (Box 49)
  - A Mama Fun Der Velt, undated (Box 49)
  - Mayn Sike, undated (Box 50)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061865 7
  - Mayn Zindele, undated (Box 50)
  - Medinal Yisroel, undated (Box 50)
  - Mit Hoyz'n, undated (Box 50)
  - Moyshe, undated (Box 50)
  - Mother's Day, undated (Box 50)
  - Nigun, undated (Box 50)
  - PoChassidatskumu, undated (Box 50)
  - Royt Armeyish, undated (Box 50)
  - ShabbatShalom, undated (Box 50)
  - Shabes, undated (Box 50)
  - Shabes Tsu Nakht, undated (Box 50)
  - Shteyn, undated (Box 50)
  - S'iz Sheyn in Libe Shpil'n, undated (Box 50)
  - Tsuder Khasene, undated (Box 50)
  - Unzer America, undated (Box 50)
  - Veyn KalleVeyn, undated (Box 50)
  - Beohovto Lereyakho Komokho, undated (Box 50)
  - Bolga, undated (Box 50)
  - Younin, undated (Box 50)
  - Zug Farvus, undated (Box 50)
- Series VII. Art Songs
  - Adondy Roi, undated (Box 51)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061866 5
  - Al Naharos Bavel, undated (Box 51)
  - Alinu Al Admateinu, undated (Box 51)
  - Allein, undated (Box 51)
  - Avodim Hoyinu, undated (Box 51)
  - Belagoles, undated (Box 51)
  - Baym Kamp Fire, undated (Box 51)
  - Blinded to His Nurse, undated (Box 51)
  - A Bobe Mayse, undated (Box 51)
  - Brivelach, undated (Box 51)
  - Chad Gadyo, undated (Box 51)
  - Chanele, undated (Box 51)
  - ChazanimTzu Probe, undated (Box 51)
  - Der Becher, undated (Box 51)
  - Der Chaz'n Un Gabay, undated (Box 51)
  - Der Cheyder Ying'l, undated (Box 51)
  - Der Farmogt Per'l, undated (Box 51)
  - Der Gilgul, undated (Box 51)
  - Der Lamdin, undated (Box 51)
  - Der Limud, undated (Box 51)
  - Di Ep'l Farkoyferin, undated (Box 51)
  - Di Royz, undated (Box 51)
  - DiZun Un Der Reg'n, undated (Box 51)
  - Dos Griebele Feld, undated (Box 51)
  - Dos HarbateShnayder'l, undated (Box 51)
  - Dayn Kumem, undated (Box 52)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061867 3
  - Dos KleyneShnayder'l, undated (Box 52)
  - Dos Yiddishe, undated (Box 52)
  - Lid, undated (Box 52)
  - Doyne Vocalise, undated (Box 52)
  - Eybik, undated (Box 52)
  - Eyns,Tsvey, Dray, Fir, undated (Box 52)
  - Eretz Yisroel, undated (Box 52)
  - Es Foylt, undated (Box 52)
  - Farvos Zingt A Chaz'n, undated (Box 52)
  - Fir Blumen, undated (Box 52)
  - The Flower of Beauty, undated (Box 52)
  - Foters, undated (Box 52)
  - FunFarsheydene Yor'n, undated (Box 52)
  - Fun Unzer Khorev Yiddish Leb'n, undated (Box 52)
  - Gele Late, undated (Box 52)
  - Geyt a Meydele Oyf'n Feld, undated (Box 52)
  - Hod'lMit Der Nod'l, undated (Box 52)
  - In Midbor Zingt Der Bedoin, undated (Box 52)
  - ItsikShpitsik, undated (Box 52)
  - A Kholem Iz Dos Leybn, undated (Box 53)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061868 1
  - Kum Shoyn Moshiakh, undated (Box 53)
  - Ligt An Alter Boym, undated (Box 53)
  - Mame Losh'n, undated (Box 53)
  - Mames Brokhe, undated (Box 53)
  - Mensh'n Lomir Bentsh'n Z'miros, undated (Box 53)
  - Meyer'l Un Pesele, undated (Box 53)
  - Mima'amakim, undated (Box 53)
  - OyFeygele, undated (Box 53)
  - Prusi Iz A Ketsele Ying'l Tsing'l, undated (Box 53)
  - Rode, Rode,Rahne, undated (Box 53)
  - Shayn Lanterne Shayn, undated (Box 53)
  - Shlof Ayn Mayn Kino, undated (Box 53)
  - Shir Hicheirut, undated (Box 53)
  - Shtey Oyf, undated (Box 53)
  - Tel Shalom, undated (Box 53)
  - T'file, undated (Box 53)
  - Three Songsin Russian, undated (Box 53)
  - Toyb'n, Toyb'n Taybelakh, undated (Box 53)
  - Trr,TrrRu, undated (Box 53)
  - Tsen Hener Mit a Katshke, undated (Box 53)
  - Tsu Mayne Lezer, undated (Box 54)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061869 9
  - Tsvey Shbester, undated (Box 54)
  - Tsvey Zilberne Becher, undated (Box 54)
  - Tsveyerley Trer'n, undated (Box 54)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 54)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 54)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 54)
  - Beyn Nit Yingele, undated (Box 54)
  - Ven Ikj Zol Zayn A Shnayder, undated (Box 54)
  - Ver S'Hot Per'l, undated (Box 54)
  - Vigilid, undated (Box 54)
  - Vilne, undated (Box 54)
  - Volga, Volga, undated (Box 54)
  - Vos Iz Mit Dir, undated (Box 54)
  - Y'hi Rotson, undated (Box 54)
  - Yesh Li Gan, undated (Box 54)
  - Yossel Ber, undated (Box 54)
  - Zamd Un Shter'n, undated (Box 54)
  - Zing Shtil, undated (Box 54)
  - Zol Noch Zayn Shabes, undated (Box 54)
- Series VIII. Hebrew Songs -Arrangements
  - Achshav, undated (Box 55)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061870 7
  - Adama, undated (Box 55)
  - Adarim, undated (Box 55)
  - Al Tira, undated (Box 55)
  - Am Yisroel Chai, undated (Box 55)
  - Anu Olim Hayom, undated (Box 55)
  - Artza Alinu, undated (Box 55)
  - Beit Ya'akov / Al Naharot Bavel, undated (Box 55)
  - Emek, undated (Box 55)
  - Hamek Hu Chalom, undated (Box 56)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061871 5
  - Israeli, undated (Box 56)
  - Hashiveinu, undated (Box 56)
  - Hava Nagilah, undated (Box 56)
  - Heiveinu Shalom Aleichem, undated (Box 56)
  - Isreali Potpourri, undated (Box 57)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061872 3
  - KatsirBaemek, undated (Box 57)
  - Ki Mitzion, undated (Box 57)
  - Lo El Sachar, undated (Box 57)
  - Ma Tov Chelkeinu, undated (Box 57)
  - Maym, undated (Box 57)
  - Ose Shalom, undated (Box 57)
  - Rad Halailah, undated (Box 57)
  - Shalom Lach Yerushalayim, undated (Box 57)
  - Shir Eres, undated (Box 58)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061873 1
  - Shir Hoavodah, undated (Box 58)
  - ShirHacheivut, undated (Box 58)
  - Shir Hapalmach, undated (Box 58)
  - Torah Orah, undated (Box 58)
  - Tsena, Tsena, undated (Box 58)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 58)
  - UriAdama and Uri Dvorah, undated (Box 58)
  - V'Af Al Pi Chein, undated (Box 58)
  - Yerushalayim, undated (Box 58)
  - Yerushalayim Shel Zahav, undated (Box 58)
  - ZaitiLoruach Archati, undated (Box 58)
- Series IX. Orchestral Arrangements
  - Fantasia Folkslider, undated (Box 59)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061874 9
  - Favorites of1923-24, undated (Box 59)
  - Hebraic Potpourri, undated (Box 59)
  - Hebraischer Tants, undated (Box 59)
  - The Lord Will Rebuild, undated (Box 59)
  - My Walking Stick, undated (Box 59)
  - Nigun (Ba'al Shem Tov), undated (Box 59)
  - Proch Variations, undated (Box 60)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04061875 6